If I ask you guys what is this
product, then you are going to answer here
that it is a remote. If I
ask you guys here what is this thing, then
you will tell here that it is a mouse,
how does it work? This is human vision.
What happens in human vision is that what our
eye does is that it
sees any product and
whatever signal it has after seeing it, that signal
reaches the mind and our mind analyzes that process and
gives us the perfect answer that you should have for it.
Now today we are going to talk
about computer vision here,
what is computer vision and how is it done,
along with this, if we talk about
where its real time is used, we are going to understand
about all these things through today's video.
I Gaurav welcome you all
to that YouTube channel
where we will talk about computer vision,
what is computer vision,
like right now I have
taken an example in the beginning that if I
show you a mouse, then you will see it  By identifying the structure, we tell that
this is a mouse, so our
computer,
you must have seen different types of devices in the computer,
like you must have seen inside the mobile that there is a
face detection app or there are
object detection apps inside the mobile, here they detect
any object and
tell information about it,
so how does all this work, so
all this works with the help of computer vision,
computer user is
a branch of your computer science, through which what you do is that whatever
real time
entities are running with you, the entertainment
data is captured in the
form of such image files, such as video files,
then it is processed in it and after processing, whatever
data they have to take
useful from it, by using that data,
it tells us the right answer here, this
fall of computer vision, so basically talking about computer vision is to
capture your real time entities
and after capturing, whatever
answer you have, provide that answer here,
now it is real time.  It does
not mean that you cannot take the past data.
Absolutely past data means if you have any
previous images and if
you want to extract any data from it, then
you can extract that data too. So basically, let's talk about the
eye of a human being. For example,
you have a nose
and skin. What do they do with it? They do
different types of sensing.
After sensing, they give
you information about the product or the data.
Similarly,
in a computer, if I want to take data through the computer, then
for that also we have
different types of systems. If
we talk about it, then the camera is a very
important quantity, what does it do to you? It
gives you different images and after that, it
works on those images and
shows you the answer. So,
what do we call this whole process? It is
called computer vision. See, here I have
shown two types of vision. One is the human vision
system and the second is what you have -
human vision.  Inside the vision system, the ice was
sensed and then it was shown to our brain
and the brain gave us the answer by giving us a signal
that there is a ball inside it,
inside the ball there is an orange, a banana, a lemon
and many other items have been made. Similarly, if we
talk about computer vision, then
what does computer vision do, its sensing
devices, for example, there is a camera,
you have many other types of
sensors here, from them it senses about the product and after
sensing it
tells our system and the system
tells us the output here that it is a bowl, an orange, a
lemon, it is told in this way, so
basically this is computer vision, so
basically if we talk about the
data that the computer gives us in the output by sensing, it is
called
computer vision, now what tasks can we perform through computer vision,
so basically
through computer vision we
can classify the object here,
like if I come in front of the computer
for this remote, then it tells us the remote,
if I bring this mouse, then
basically it comes here, so in this
way  What is happening with you is that to classify your
objects, it
means that you have a lot of
objects being kept inside the group of data,
like here you have
a lot of apples, grapes inside a bowl,
along with this, bananas, mangoes and
many other things have been kept here, so
despite that, what did they do, they classified those things,
here this is orange,
here this grapes, these are bananas, dates, in this
way, if we talk, then the
tasks related to such classification are
performed here through computer vision. The
second thing is
about identification of any
object, if you want to
identify which
object is this, what is it that is working from the head, then what
we have, the identification
work
can also be done through computer vision. Next is
object tracking, if
you want to track an object,
how that object is moving,
where it is moving, then that can also be done by
restoring the image.
Restoring means that you have an
old image, in today's time, all of you must have
seen one thing that many old
images are converted into the
new generation images of today,
color is filled in it,
it is modified in a different way,
this is called an image ridge string,
so you can also restore old, very old
images,
you can remove many techniques like color filling etc. in them with the help of computer vision,
after that feature matching feature happens, if
you want to match one feature that is matching with other features
or not,
one object is
not matching with another object, in this
way you can do it here,
video motion is like here, so
what are all these, which are
performed under computer vision,
so basically I want to talk about computer vision,
so computer vision is a
branch through which  You
work on the video and images file and
whatever data was to be extracted from it, all the
information of the data is extracted and work is done on it. If we
talk about the second thing, then
apart from photos and images, if you
talk about 3D images here, then that too is
performed here.
How does computer vision work with us? So
what does computer vision do?
First of all, it collects images here.
You may have many images,
which may be in 3D, there may be 2D
images, there may be real time images, there
may be videos. If we
talk about the video, then there are images inside the video as well.
Actually,
what happens inside the video, the resolution is reduced within a second on the frame. That
means the
video that you see here is
also done by joining small images inside it.
Here a
video file is created here. If we
talk about it here, then what do you have?
You have a lot of different images that are
collected here.
After that, it is processed.
What do you do inside processing,
here you
can use machine learning, you
can follow different processing here
or through images, if
you have to perform any operation on it,
like I have to restore the image, then
that too will be called a part of this processing.
After that, what do you have,
understanding image, means
inside this you are
told the understanding about the image, how this image will be
identified to you,
if classification is to be done, then
how classification is going to happen, all these things are
defined here, so
what do we do inside computer vision, we
collect data, that means we collect images, we
process them and
after processing, whatever
understanding comes inside it is
shown in front of you all, now let us talk about the application of
computer vision inside the real world, so
first of all, here for virtual reality, the
most used here is
object detection app, which  Object detection is done to find out
which object is what. It is
mostly used for this
and in the medical field, it is used to
identify any disease.
If there is a healthy person and an unhealthy
person, then how do you know the difference between them?
Because nowadays, you must know that in the medical
field, you are mostly working on the match
because they have
X-rays.
Along with this, you have
many things like indus copy etc. through which you can
know whether you have a disease or not. So, you do that
through computer vision. The
best and most popular
example is self-driving. If I talk about self-
driving, yes,
what does it do to you in self-driving and computer
vision is used the most
because in self-driving,
you have many cameras
which take your real-time image
and how to work with it here with real-time image,
that is done by your fast
experience.  What do you do?
Work follows that. So, the real-
time image that is coming to you, how is it
coming, how is it working,
your work is done on that. So basically,
in the real world, computer vision is used a
lot. So
basically, in today's time,
computer vision is a very good field in which
you can make your career.
Through computer vision, you
work on images and videos in a good way and connect different types of information,
etc. In the next video,
we are going to look at computer vision in more
detail. We will
talk about an OpenCC model of it, which is
a fighting library and through it
computer tasks can be performed.
We are going to perform all those tasks one by one. So, that's all for
today's video.
See you in our
next video. Till you stay with us
like this, keep it up. Good bye
[Prashant]
[Music]